# Jillo Woche

Full Stack Software Engineer

#### Profile

Skilled Full Stack Software Engineer with over 4 years of experience, and a track record of delivering high-quality software solutions. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team.

# Employment History

## Full Stack Software Engineer at Syndicate Protocol, Nairobi

April 2021 — March 2023

- 1. Successfully built (from the ground up) and deployed a performant web app within 3 months using TypeScript/ReactJS.
- 2. Collaborated with team members to develop and deploy a GraphQL back-end API to store off-chain data within a month.
- 3. Investigated and fixed bug reports on the company web app within 4 hours at the most.

# Front-end Engineer at Cellulant, Nairobi

November 2019 — March 2021

- 1. Worked closely with the design team to dramatically improve the accessibility and user-friendliness of applications with React and NextJS.
- 2. Continuously iterated over front-end web apps and used observation tools like Hotjar to significantly improve user payment flows for over 6 payment options.

## Full-Stack Software Engineer at Andela Kenya Ltd, Nairobi

November 2018 — September 2019

- 1. Collaborated with the design team to quickly and efficiently build front-end apps using ReactJS.
- 2. Collaborated with team members to build and deploy a performant REST API using Python/Django within a month.

#### Team Leader at Samasource Kenya Ltd, Nairobi

June 2016 — November 2018

1. Supervised and coordinated the work efforts of a team of 22 leading to the success of a major pilot project.

# Education

Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology, Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology, Nairobi

January 2012 — January 2015 Grade: First Class Honors.

#### ■ References

Will Papper, Co-founder and CEO from Syndicate

will@syndicate.io

Nathan Hausman, Head of Engineering from Syndicate

nate.hausman@gmail.com

### **Victor Mutai from Syndicate**

victormutaijambo@gmail.com · +254729021209

#### **Details**

Nairobi Kenya

0720471303

jayloabdullahi@gmail.com

Date / Place of birth

June 1990

Marsabit, Kenya

Nationality

Kenyan

#### Links

Projects Portfolio LinkedIn Profile Github Profile

#### **Skills**

JavaScript

ReactJS

Typescript

**NextJS** 

Web3/dApp development

HTML5/CSS3

GraphQL/Apollo/REST APIs

Databases(Postgres, NoSQL)

#### Languages

English

Swahili

#### **Hobbies**

Following up on the latest in tech including crypto. Playing soccer and console games.

Movies and music.